PATRICK VEVERKA

SUMMARY

I am a proven software developer and manager with over two decades of experience developing cutting edge applications. I love learning new languages and applying them to real world situations

Specialties: Elixir, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Python, AWS, Go, Rust

WORK HISTORY

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, FLATIRON SCHOOL (PART OF WEWORK) (REMOTE)

January 2018 to present

Created internal tooling to provide reliable continuous integration and deployment for large development team

Created architectural review board and mentored developers through internal talks and pairing sessions

Designed and implemented AWS Lambda based ETL framework to generate reports from Data Warehouse

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, HAMMER CORPORATION (REMOTE)

July 2017 to January 2018

Developed framework to modernize high volume Twilio SMS application Expanded Business Chat application to include Facebook Messenger Worked on internal tools that greatly increased developer productivity

DIRECTOR OF ENGINEERING, WOMBAT SECURITY TECHNOLOGIES (REMOTE)

October 2015 to Present

Worked with internal teams to fully integrate Java and Ruby platforms by moving to a microservice architecture

Implemented zero downtime deployments and evangelized immutable infrastructure to new team members

Expanded remote team by hiring contractors and full-time employees across Ember, Ruby and Elixir

DIRECTOR OF ENGINEERING, THREATSIM (REMOTE)

March 2012 to October 2015

Led international development, operations and QA team for SaaS startup from beginning to successful acquisition

Hired and mentored junior developers from development bootcamps

Converted original .NET application into scalable, multi-tiered Ruby application

LEAD DEVELOPER, GEICO (VIRGINIA BEACH)

January 2009 - March 2012

Supported multi-user client/server integration effort

Mentored junior developers in proper coding techniques

Presented on diverse topics to internal "lunch and learn" meetings

LEAD DEVELOPER, PIKUM! (REMOTE)

January 2007 – January 2009

Created next generation meta-gaming infrastructure for gambling startup
Responsible for full software development life cycle of n-tier software solution
Developed high frequency services to reliably import partner data feeds
containing thousands of sporting events

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT, EURO RSCG DISCOVERY/HAVAS (REMOTE)

October 2005 – January 2007

Designed large scale marketing system for external client utilizing custom search engine integration, credit card processing and management of over 400,000 members

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, COX AUTO TRADER (NORFOLK)

January 2004 – October 2005

Developed Tablet PC application utilizing web services to communicate with legacy systems and backend data tier

Researched and proposed technology update for EDI application including rewrite in .NET and web interface for external partners

Interfaced with various groups within and outside of company on system wide technology refresh

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

Old Dominion University, Norfolk, VA